<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blog | Lucas' Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.eagleton.org/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.eagleton.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-09T13:13:17+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.eagleton.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MuzzleFork]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renewed interest]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.eagleton.org/2013/06/renewed-interest/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T11:52:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.eagleton.org/2013/06/renewed-interest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, it looks like the <a href="/2012/11/another-new-blogging-engine/">pledge</a> I made when I replaced WordPress with Octopress for my blog didn't last too long - i.e. I didn't even get one article out after making that pledge. That's pretty poor.<!-- More --></p>

<p>Over the last few weekends, I've caught up with an <a href="https://twitter.com/sammyjarrett">old buddy</a> to get our nerd on and work on some nerdy things. This weekend, we looked at Octopress (in the interest of setting it up for him) and it got me interested in posting more. So, here's a new theme (so it's not stock-standard Octopress flavour) and hopefully more of a commitment to getting some content out there..</p>

<p>I've recently completed Certified Scrum Master training and have deployed some websites to a new hosting setup with <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=1d72a90eb581">Digital Ocean</a> (NB: Referral code embedded in that link) which I've found to be a fast, cheap and easy way to manage a host for the nerdier amongst us. Expect some posts in the coming weeks covering some of those topics.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another new blogging engine]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.eagleton.org/2012/11/another-new-blogging-engine/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T21:11:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.eagleton.org/2012/11/another-new-blogging-engine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog tends to get updated... sporadically. I get the energy to post more often and that generally results in transferring the content from one blog engine to another - sometimes the new blog doesn't even get a new post. This time, I'm changing from wordpress to octopress, living in GitHub pages and I guess, once again, I'll pledge to post more often.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Benefits</h2>

<ul>
<li>I can hack away on posts in <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text 2</a> and deploy them whenever I'm ready.</li>
<li>I can write my posts in markdown which is great.</li>
<li>I found a great <a href="https://github.com/blueplanet/sublime-text-2-octopress">octopress plugin for sublime</a> which is really handy and to which I've been able to contribute some changes and features to.</li>
<li>Octopress and Jekyll are in ruby, ST2 plugins are in python and the existing templates use LESS. A nice change to my day-to-day life as a PHP developer to hack around in some new technologies.</li>
<li>Performance of effectively static media via GitHub pages is much better than loading pages through wordpress' database driven structure. See if you can tell when I changed the hosting arrangement in the graph below.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="[class names]" src="/images/wordpress-octopress-performance.png" width="678" height="454" title="Page load performance improvement - guess when I changed the hosting arrangement" ></p>

<h2>Detractors</h2>

<ul>
<li>I actually really liked wordpress' stats available through JetPack. I've set up Google Analytics, but while it's probably a better product, it's just not as friendly.</li>
<li>Wordpress has so many themes available. This is possibly a benefit though - I used to get <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_paralysis">analysis paralysis</a> in attempting to decide which one to use.</li>
</ul>


<p>Let's see how I go. Hereby pledging (once again) to post more often, keeping it technical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
